It's not the house that's haunted.
Insidious is a horror, thriller film directed by James Wan.
A family discovers that dark spirits have invaded their home after
their son inexplicably falls into an endless sleep.
When they reach out to a professional for help, they learn
things are a lot more personal than they thought.
Josh Lambert, played by Patrick Wilson.
Renai Lambert, played by Rose Byrne.
Elise Rainier, played by Lin Shaye.
Dalton Lambert, played by Ty Simpkins.
Lorraine Lambert, played by Barbara Hershey.
Specs, played by Leigh Whannell.
Insidious is a 2010 supernatural horror film directed and co-edited by James Wan, written by
Leigh Whannell, and starring Patrick Wilson, Rose Byrne, and Barbara Hershey.
It is the first installment in the Insidious franchise and the
third in terms of the series' in-story chronology.
The story centers on a married couple whose boy inexplicably enters a comatose state and
becomes a vessel for a variety of demonic entities in an astral plane.
Insidious had its world premiere on September 14, 2010, at the 2010 Toronto International Film
Festival (TIFF) and received a wide theatrical release on April 1, 2011, by FilmDistrict.
The film is followed by two sequels, Insidious: Chapter 2 (2013), Insidious: The Red Door (2023);
and two prequels, Insidious: Chapter 3 (2015) and Insidious: The Last Key (2018).
The film explores themes of medium, haunted house,
evil spirit, house warming, new home.
The tone is dark and intense.